<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-12T17:16:37+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Zanark’s Blog</title><subtitle>I am a noob programmer who likes to automate stuff.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Programmer stuck in a rut</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Programmer stuck in a rut" /><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut.html">&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter how successful you are or how hard-working you are or how easily you can get motivated to do something, eventually you’ll reach a point in your life where you’ll start loosing interest in everything. You’ll start feeling comfortable with not challenging yourself anymore. You won’t be able to get inspired and motivated from any new challenges. You won’t be able to bring up the desire to take an action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that rendered you useless can be anything, it can be a bug which you’re just unable to rectify, it can be a badly documented API, or maybe its just because you are a JAVA Programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can actually come also after success as well, maybe you’re starting to feel less motivated while solving even the most challenging questions, maybe you are feeling comfortable with the status of your app and dont want to add any new features to ruin its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you can relate to anything close to what I mentioned above then you might be in a rut and its totally okay. Trust me it happens to the best of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to give you some of the best tips that I’ve learned from other people to et yourself out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-start-small&quot;&gt;1. Start Small.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in a rut, you just dont feel like doing anything, like nothing at all. Even the thought of a small task like setting up your bed can exhaust you and make you feel unmotivated instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of looking at the as a whole, break ‘em down to smaller tasks that you can complete quickly. This gives you a small shot of motivation and that sweet lil dope-a-mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting small is the key, you can then slowly combine everything and finish that task which was daunting on you without getting exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-set-your-priorities-and-use-your-time-judiciously&quot;&gt;2. Set your priorities and use your time judiciously.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create a time-table for the day, you must have found yourself putting every task at hand on the plate which make you run out of time to do other tasks. Trust me this happens to everyone. You might want to complete all the tasks in a single day but all of us only get 24 hrs, and &lt;strong&gt;sleep is important&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So set your priorities straight. If you want to have fun that day, then focus on what brings you joy at what time of the day and do not let anything disrupt the time alloted to fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stick to your priorities and you’ll be able to finish all the tasks and this time there wont be a pile of laundry on the back of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-dont-let-yourself-get-bored&quot;&gt;3. Don’t let yourself get bored.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boredom brings sadness. It’ll make you think about your life, all the bad choices you made in the past, whether you are happy or not etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It basically brings too much unpleasantness with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t let yourself get bored, go draw, learn something new, go out and play, try someone else’s Spotify playlist, watch a new movie/anime/tv-series/whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-connect-to-people-who-inspire-you&quot;&gt;4. Connect to people who inspire you.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the average of the 5 people you spend most of your time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you hang out with people who have achieved something in their lives or are striving towards achieving something, you get inspired do something in your life too. They might not know about this but they are your indirect mentors. Seeing them persue something ignites a fire inside you and when this fire spreads to other people, they too get motivated to do something and then this cycle goes on and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these were a few tips that I’ve been trying to implement in my life since past 3 weeks and it has motivated me to keep on pushing harder and increase my work stamina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video that inspired me to write this Blog Post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zUr9n0Hy3PA&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So goodbye ppl, and keep learning new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><summary type="html">It doesn’t matter how successful you are or how hard-working you are or how easily you can get motivated to do something, eventually you’ll reach a point in your life where you’ll start loosing interest in everything. You’ll start feeling comfortable with not challenging yourself anymore. You won’t be able to get inspired and motivated from any new challenges. You won’t be able to bring up the desire to take an action.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My C# and .NET journal</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/10/My-C-and-.NET-Journal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My C# and .NET journal" /><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/10/My-C#-and-.NET-Journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/10/My-C-and-.NET-Journal.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zanark/Blog/master/media/CNET%20Thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;C# .NET Tutorial series Thumbail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve started a new series on my YouTube channel - C# and .NET Tutorial Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its kind of like a video journal that keeps track of my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/uLdNytpAIcI&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to upload all the code to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Zanark/L-NET/&quot;&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try my best to upload 1 video every 2 days, I hope I’ll be able to actually do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Interview Experience</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/01/My-Interview-Experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Interview Experience" /><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/01/My-Interview-Experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/01/My-Interview-Experience.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Hope you all are fine and dandy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as you can see, this is the first genuine post on my blog and I would like to make it as useful as possible.
Therefore, I’m going to share my interview experience here, hoping it might help some people out and provide
them with an idea of how the interview process looks and feels like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-0---written-exam&quot;&gt;ROUND 0 - Written Exam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exam was held on 19th June and the reporting time was 1PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s just skip to the meat(paneer if you are a vegetarian), the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Exam was held on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mettl.com/&quot;&gt;mettl&lt;/a&gt;, and it had 4 sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alloted Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 1 : Analytical and Quantitative – 20 Questions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;20 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 2 : Hands on Programming – 2 Questions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;25 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 3 : Tech MCQ – 20 Questions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;20 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 4 : Written English Test : 1 Question&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;20 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-1--analytical-and-quantitative&quot;&gt;Section 1 : Analytical and Quantitative&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relative Directional Questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete a pattern&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some Basic Maths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-2--hands-on-programming&quot;&gt;Section 2 : Hands on Programming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 basic programming puzzle questions where you’ll have to use different data structures and algorithms to get the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearing the hidden test cases is the key to clearing this round&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-3--tech-mcq&quot;&gt;Section 3 : Tech MCQ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DBMS, OS, and other theory based questions.
It had some networking questions as well. Many people struggled here, but people who have studied subjects out of the syllabus of the current semester were able to crack it(basically people who go to GATE or any other coaching classes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-4--written-english-test&quot;&gt;Section 4 : Written English Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we were given a topic to write an essay on.
The topic I got was - &lt;em&gt;The effect of media on one’s social development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of the written exam were declared on 22nd June, and luckily I was able to clear the written exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then asked to get ready for the Technical Interview which was going to be held on 24th June, yep, we had only 2 days to prepare for the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2 days of preparation, THE DAY came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my defence, I was &lt;strong&gt;REALLY&lt;/strong&gt; nervous. So if you saw me chowing down on chocolates and acting all goofy, I was basically trying to calm myself down with dopamine hits.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-1---the-technical-interview&quot;&gt;ROUND 1 - The Technical Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This round consisted of a one-on-one interview with one of the panel members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panel member asked for my Resume and briefly went through it.
&lt;br /&gt;
He then asked me one of the most feared questions: &lt;em&gt;” Tell me more about yourself “&lt;/em&gt;. Honestly, at first I was dumbfounded because I honestly wasn’t expecting that question in a technical round. I told him about my background and about all of my projects and the experience I gained in my internships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then started talking about my GitHub profile and about the open source projects that I’ve contributed to. He then checked my GitHub profile and my pinned repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the introductions, he gave me some simple math problems to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A friendly tip: BREATHE IN, BREATHE OUT, its okay to feel nervous, 
so take your time and calm down and solve the problem.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find such math problems on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/company-interview-corner/&quot;&gt;GeeksforGeeks&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuler.net/archives&quot;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt; and practice there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit that I was pretty nervous and it took me longer than expected to solve the questions, and the interviewer was also very friendly and provided me with some hints for which I respect him a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After discussing a bit more about my projects he asked me questions from Computer Science Fundamentals, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OOPs Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DBMS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Algorithms and Data Structures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Complexity and Space Complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also asked me to code some Dynamic Programming Algorithms. I wasn’t able to answer all the questions, but was able to give an outline of the approach one will take to solve the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it, I thanked the interviewer and headed back to the waiting room to join my peers banging their heads on the wall.&lt;br /&gt;
I too was really disappointed in myself for not being able to solve some of the basic questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-2---the-personal-interview&quot;&gt;ROUND 2 - The Personal Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard that I got selected for Round 2, I honestly couldn’t believe it. I tried my best to hold my racing heart and the excitement in and took deep breaths to calm myself down and then headed for the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered the interviewer’s cabin, greeted her and took a seat.&lt;br /&gt;
She asked me for my Resume and told me that she was pretty impressed by my GitHub profile.&lt;br /&gt;
I honestly cannot express how glad I was for mentioning my GitHub profile on my Resume and during the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;So remember kids, your GitHub profile is your second Resume.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then started talking about my experiences while developing the projects(both good and bad), internship experiences(both good and bad), my hobbies and interests, my weaknesses and how I keep myself updated in this ever-changing world of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also asked me some Client-Consultant scenario questions, about how I’ll solve a problem reported by a client and how I’ll keep the client updated on the progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was it, I thanked her and left the cabin with a huge smile because for me, the personal interview went really well and I was able to answer the interviewer’s questions well. I’ll be honest, I was proud of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-3---an-interview-with-the-hr&quot;&gt;ROUND 3 - An Interview with the HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a smile on my face and a boost in confidence from Round 2, I headed for the interview room for the 3rd round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HR was an incredibly friendly and charming person, a perfect gentleman. He actually asked me for my Resume on the doorstep and I almost dropped it while handing it to him, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then started going through my Resume and asked me about my Projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did I choose to make this project?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will I sell my project?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the world really need my solution to a problem whose solution already exists?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the person I am trying to convince to buy my product doesn’t agree at all then what should I do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was basically asked questions about my projects and what I can do with them and what kind of people is my project going to help and how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty confident and satisfied about how my third round went. I was even ready to accept rejection because this interview experience taught me a lot about how interviews go and what interviewers look for in a candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I calmed myself down and waited for my results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just kidding, I wasnt able to calm myself down. I couldn’t sit down in a place because when I did my stomach started feelling funny because of all that nervousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour of struggle to calm myself down, the panel members entered the room with the list of selected students, and yes, I got selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so happy that I just couldn’t stop smilling because of which my jaw muscles started to pain.
Now, I was just standing there with a locked jaw smiling like a goof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yep, that’s how my Interview went….in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will soon upload another post where I’ll add some Interview and Resume tips that I picked up from places on the internet. Until then goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, &lt;strong&gt;KEEP LEARNING NEW STUFF!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><summary type="html">Hello everyone! Hope you all are fine and dandy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Deployment test</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/30/Deployment-Test-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deployment test" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/30/Deployment-Test-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/30/Deployment-Test-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><summary type="html">This is a test post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/22/First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2019-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/22/First-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/22/First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently live streaming, hop in if you wanna see how much of an idiot i look like while programming lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube Channel Name: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwnUr0cB24YKbafp2wwQK2w&quot;&gt;ZANARK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwnUr0cB24YKbafp2wwQK2w/live&quot; title=&quot;My Live Stream&quot;&gt;Join me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><summary type="html">This is the first post on this blog.</summary></entry></feed>