<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-18T18:43:58+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Zanark’s Blog</title><subtitle>I am a noob programmer who likes to automate stuff.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">GameDev Diary #1</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2020/02/18/GameDev-Diary-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GameDev Diary #1" /><published>2020-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2020/02/18/GameDev-Diary-#1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2020/02/18/GameDev-Diary-1.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;gamedev-diary-1&quot;&gt;GameDev Diary #1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to learn C#, and whats the best way to learn C# other than making Games and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with MonoGame just like how a friend suggested, however I just cant bring up the motivation
to sit and work on it right now. Honestly, I have no idea where did all of my creative will vanish off to.
However, now I have some idea as to where I can start from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamefromscratch.com/post/2013/08/01/Just-starting-out-what-games-should-I-make.aspx&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; written by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCr-5TdGkKszdbboXXsFZJTQ&quot;&gt;Youtuber GamesFromScratch (check him out, he’s awesome)&lt;/a&gt; and realised something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot make a RPG games as a beginner, even though I have some programming language experience, I CANNOT!
NO ONE CAN! IT WIL TAKE TIME!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just don’t know why I was unable to understand something so obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I really dont wanna waste anymore time. Imma start today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html">GameDev Diary #1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Federated Learning</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2020/01/09/Federated-Learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Federated Learning" /><published>2020-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2020/01/09/Federated-Learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2020/01/09/Federated-Learning.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey all! Happy New Year! 2020!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been working on my machine learning skills which are pretty much non existent, and now I have been assigned a new task by my mentor…which is to learn  how federated learning works. So I’m just gonna document what I learned here. Hope its informative ^_^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;federated-learning&quot;&gt;Federated Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-federated-learning&quot;&gt;What is federated learning?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In federated learning the data is decentralised. This means that the data provided to the model is recieved from different sources simultaneously. For example getting data for a model form different mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-federated-learning&quot;&gt;Why federated learning?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventionally, the machine learning model works on the server and data is provided to the server by different clients. However this has some limitations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The server is online therefore poor internet will cause latency in getting results from the server, and such a case is not ideal for a model aiming for real-time results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The application cannot work offline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The network over which the data is sent is not secure enough therefore sensitive data can get leaked.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending and recieving data over a network is expensive for the battery and for the user as it’ll take up a lot of data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, what if the model is on the phone? This way teh model and the data is inside the moile phone.Well that has its own limitations as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s not enough data for the model.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Training and testing can use up a lot of battery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eg: What if a new word gets introduced in the dictionary and everyone else is using it but the user, this way the user doesn’t have the data for that word locally and the model will never know about it, and therefore this feature will never get discovered by the user unless he gets to know about it from an external source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well then, what if the model is pretrained a bit on the server using some proxy data, and then is sent to the clients for further training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solution might sound optimal but we can never decide on the perfect proxy data that can be used to pretrain the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in essence federated learning is kind of like collaborative learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the server send an initial model(which is not pretrained on any data) to all the clients. The clients then train and test the model on their own local data. When all the clients are done with trainig their models, their modified models is then pushed to the server which then takes an average of the modified model and send it back to the clients. So as you can see, we have a cycle here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-about-privacy&quot;&gt;Now about Privacy..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons why federated learning is so successfull is that it handles privacy really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The data never left the clients device =&amp;gt; sensitive data was never shared over the network =&amp;gt; secure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can trust the servers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Server cannot log any data from the clients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differential Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;: Each client adds some noise to the data they provide to the server. With a large number of clients, the noise generated on the       server-side creates a mask over the data it recieves which makes it difficult to point out individuality of the data still maintaing the progressibilty        of the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="machine-learning" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">Hey all! Happy New Year! 2020!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Linux Ricing</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/12/28/What-is-Linux-Ricing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Linux Ricing" /><published>2019-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/12/28/What-is-Linux-Ricing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/12/28/What-is-Linux-Ricing.html">&lt;p&gt;Yo ppl, guess the year is about to end and I havent uploaded a vid on my channel for a long time….nor have I posted nything on my blog here……kek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been asked by a lot of people - What the fuck is ricing? How do I do it?..and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So according to the favourite social hub of introverted virgin nerds(like me)…reddit and a subreddit where Arch users will never stop flexing, r/unixporn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Rice” is a word that is commonly used to refer to making visual improvements and customizations on one’s desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “ricing” was inheritted from the practice of customizing or modifying cars in Asia to make them look…..cool?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zanark/Blog/master/media/riced_car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;riced_car&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being racist, the word is accepted by the majority of the community and is used sparingly to refer to a visually attractive desktop upgraded beyond the default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so how does one start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-choose-your-distro&quot;&gt;1. Choose your distro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the unique and derived flavours of ice-creams, Linux has different distributions which have unique features and community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose which distro you want to work with and stick to it for atleast 2-3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most popular linux distros are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XUbuntu(xfce)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KUbuntu(KDE Plasma)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elementory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manjaro
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-choose-your-desktop-environment&quot;&gt;2. Choose your desktop environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desktop environment or DE is the part of the Operating System which handles the graphical user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have worked in the field of Web Development, a DE is basically the front end libraries you use to create a GUI for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of DE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KDE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xfce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gnome
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-choose-a-window-manager&quot;&gt;3. Choose a window manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A widow managers job is to manage windows…well no shit sherlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In simple words a window manager handles how the user can interact with the windows and how teh windows get displayed on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular window managers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xfce-wm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i3wm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bspwm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;awesomewm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-choose-your-terminal-emulator&quot;&gt;4. Choose your terminal emulator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terminal emulators handle how the terminal looks and allows you to customize the look if you dont like the default one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular terminal emulators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xfce4-terminal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;urxvt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tmux
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-status-bars&quot;&gt;5. Status Bars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status bars are like the task bar on Windows. It’s just like an applet that you can customize to your hearts content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular status bars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;polybar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i3bar
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-theming-icons-and-fonts&quot;&gt;6. Theming, Icons and Fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding the best theme that suits your wallpaper can be quite tough. You can use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lxapperance&lt;/code&gt; to choose themes for your windows and mouse pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing fonts is the most iritating job during ricing, however once you get it done once, the same process can be copied to other distros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can hop over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xfce-look.org/&quot;&gt;xfcelook.org&lt;/a&gt; to download some awesome themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s it, its that easy. I’ll explain every step in its own post and will post soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, happy holidays and keep learning new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="youtube" /><summary type="html">Yo ppl, guess the year is about to end and I havent uploaded a vid on my channel for a long time….nor have I posted nything on my blog here……kek.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A brief explanation of the Dark Side of the Internet</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/11/18/Darknet-TW-Speech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A brief explanation of the Dark Side of the Internet" /><published>2019-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/11/18/Darknet-TW-Speech</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/11/18/Darknet-TW-Speech.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is kind of a support material for my TW speech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure by now everyone has heard about the Dark Web, commonly known as the epicenter of illegal and illicit online activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets start from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-origin-of-the-internet&quot;&gt;The Origin of the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1969 a couple of university students sent the world’s first computer-to-computer message. It was sent over ARPANET, an early ancestor of the internet. The concept of a network or a possible means of communication between two computers was the radical idea that set into motion the early stages of what we now call the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the internet continued to grow in the mid-to-late 1990s it would come to transform society on a global scale. The biggest change came in the form of instant communication. As long as you had an internet connection you could talk to anyone on earth, assuming, of course, they were also connected to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, the internet was not designed with things like anonymity and privacy in mind so everything you do and say online can and, in many cases, will be tracked, recorded, and traceable back to you. Some people are very concerned about their privacy and in the mid 1990s one such group of people was the United States federal government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-invention-of-tor&quot;&gt;The Invention of TOR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of computer scientists and mathematicians working for a branch of the US Navy known as the Naval Research Laboratory, abbreviated as NRL, began development of a new technology known as onion routing. Onion routing would allow for anonymous bi-directional communication where the source and destination cannot be determined by a mid-point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is accomplish by creating something known as an overlay network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overlay network is simply a network that is built on top of another network, in this case the internet. So instead of using the normal unencrypted internet, also known as the surface web, your traffic goes trough an overlay network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the people over at NRL soon realized a major limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The United States government can’t simply run an anonymity system for everybody and then use it themselves only because then
every time a connection came from it people would say “Oh, it’s another CIA agent looking at my website!” if those are the only
people using the network. So you need to have other people using the network so that they blend together.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;b&gt;ROGER DINGLEDINE&lt;/b&gt; (Co-Founder and Director of THE TOR PROJECT, speaking at a conference in 2004 )&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what he’s saying is that for the network to be truly anonymous it has to be available to everyone and not just the US government. So the NRL was forced to release their onion routing technology to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology was eventually released under an open source license and became TOR. TOR stands for The Onion Router and is the software you need to download to be able to access this network of onion routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, millions of people across the globe use TOR for a multitude of purposes. Everything from innocent daily browsing to criminal activities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And while it is the most popular, TOR is but one among numerous darknets. Together they all make up the dark web. Subsequently, the dark web forms a small part of the deep web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deep web is everything on the web that can not be indexed by search engines. It’s nothing like the dark web as most of us use the deep web all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-difference-between-dark-web-and-deep-web&quot;&gt;The difference between DARK WEB and DEEP WEB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fshawglobalnews.files.wordpress.com%2F2017%2F05%2Fdark-web-iceberg.jpg%3Fquality%3D70%26strip%3Dall%26strip%3Dall&amp;amp;f=1&amp;amp;nofb=1&quot; alt=&quot;A pictorail representation fo the internet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The deep web is content that can not be indexed by search engines. And the dark web is a fraction of the deep web consisting of numerous darknets which require specific software and/or authorization to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you make your Facebook profile private, search engines will not be able to find your profile. Even Facebook’s account search engine wont show your account as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, the deep web has a lot more content than the surface web. How much more? Well, we don’t know because by its very nature it’s near-impossible to determine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper from 2001 estimated that the deep web is 500 times the size of the surface web but, then again, that estimation is almost over 2 decades old.
According to a more recent study, only 4% of the internet can be indexed by any search engines.&lt;br /&gt;
All we can say for certain is that deep web content accounts for the vast majority of the content on the world wide web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Web is just that small portion of deepweb which has extra security and is intentionally hidden from search engines.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;case-study---silk-road&quot;&gt;Case Study - Silk Road&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anonymity attracts a vast variety of people and can be used for both licit and illicit purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since the birth of the internet, people have used it for illegeal online activity. Infact one of the first E-Commerce transcations was a drug deal which was done in between two students at MIT Stanford in 1970.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October of 2013, the FBI took down the online drug marketplace known as Silk Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website had been in operation since the beginning of 2011 with a total revenue estimated at $1.2 billion. News about the Silk Road website brought the dark web out of the dark and right into public eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a few months after Silk Road had been taken down ex-administrators of the site launched Silk Road 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in late 2014, the FBI arrested the admins and the second marketplace was taken down as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few hours after that, Silk Road 3.0 was launched and the seemingly endless spiral continues. And keep in mind that Silk Road
was just one website among many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find numerous others just like it, selling every illegal drug you can imagine and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FBI also claimed that the owner of the Silk Road website had attempted to have six people killed by using deep web murder-for-hire services. While the assassinations themselves are unlikely to have occurred, these websites can definitely
be found on the dark web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.
.
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well yep I haven’t explained some stuff, especially how TOR works, I’m gonna explain that in another post that I’m working on right now and will upload soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="darknet" /><summary type="html">This is kind of a support material for my TW speech</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nope, not dead yet.</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/11/04/Nope-not-dead-yet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nope, not dead yet." /><published>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/11/04/Nope-not-dead-yet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/11/04/Nope-not-dead-yet.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Guys!! A new post on my dead blog lol :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it’s been a while since I last uploaded anything on my YouTube channel or on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well the thing is I hit a roadblock recently. I had no idea what to do and started to feel guilty about the time I have .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore I took a break this October, and I guess I have my motivation back. Expect some content soon!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">Hey Guys!! A new post on my dead blog lol :P</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Programmer stuck in a rut</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Programmer stuck in a rut" /><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut.html">&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter how successful you are or how hard-working you are or how easily you can get motivated to do something, eventually you’ll reach a point in your life where you’ll start loosing interest in everything. You’ll start feeling comfortable with not challenging yourself anymore. You won’t be able to get inspired and motivated from any new challenges. You won’t be able to bring up the desire to take an action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that rendered you useless can be anything, it can be a bug which you’re just unable to rectify, it can be a badly documented API, or maybe its just because you are a JAVA Programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can actually come also after success as well, maybe you’re starting to feel less motivated while solving even the most challenging questions, maybe you are feeling comfortable with the status of your app and dont want to add any new features to ruin its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you can relate to anything close to what I mentioned above then you might be in a rut and its totally okay. Trust me it happens to the best of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to give you some of the best tips that I’ve learned from other people to get yourself out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-start-small&quot;&gt;1. Start Small.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in a rut, you just dont feel like doing anything, like nothing at all. Even the thought of a small task like setting up your bed can exhaust you and make you feel unmotivated instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of looking at the as a whole, break ‘em down to smaller tasks that you can complete quickly. This gives you a small shot of motivation and that sweet lil dope-a-mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting small is the key, you can then slowly combine everything and finish that task which was daunting on you without getting exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-set-your-priorities-and-use-your-time-judiciously&quot;&gt;2. Set your priorities and use your time judiciously.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create a time-table for the day, you must have found yourself putting every task at hand on the plate which make you run out of time to do other tasks. Trust me this happens to everyone. You might want to complete all the tasks in a single day but all of us only get 24 hrs, and &lt;strong&gt;sleep is important&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So set your priorities straight. If you want to have fun that day, then focus on what brings you joy at what time of the day and do not let anything disrupt the time alloted to fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stick to your priorities and you’ll be able to finish all the tasks and this time there wont be a pile of laundry on the back of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-dont-let-yourself-get-bored&quot;&gt;3. Don’t let yourself get bored.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boredom brings sadness. It’ll make you think about your life, all the bad choices you made in the past, whether you are happy or not etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It basically brings too much unpleasantness with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t let yourself get bored, go draw, learn something new, go out and play, try someone else’s Spotify playlist, watch a new movie/anime/tv-series/whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-connect-to-people-who-inspire-you&quot;&gt;4. Connect to people who inspire you.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the average of the 5 people you spend most of your time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you hang out with people who have achieved something in their lives or are striving towards achieving something, you get inspired do something in your life too. They might not know about this but they are your indirect mentors. Seeing them pursue something ignites a fire inside you and when this fire spreads to other people, they too get motivated to do something and then this cycle goes on and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these were a few tips that I’ve been trying to implement in my life since past 3 weeks and it has motivated me to keep on pushing harder and increase my work stamina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video that inspired me to write this Blog Post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zUr9n0Hy3PA&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So goodbye ppl, and keep learning new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="motivation" /><summary type="html">It doesn’t matter how successful you are or how hard-working you are or how easily you can get motivated to do something, eventually you’ll reach a point in your life where you’ll start loosing interest in everything. You’ll start feeling comfortable with not challenging yourself anymore. You won’t be able to get inspired and motivated from any new challenges. You won’t be able to bring up the desire to take an action.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My C# and .NET journal</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/10/My-C-and-.NET-Journal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My C# and .NET journal" /><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/10/My-C#-and-.NET-Journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/10/My-C-and-.NET-Journal.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zanark/Blog/master/media/CNET%20Thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;C# .NET Tutorial series Thumbail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve started a new series on my YouTube channel - C# and .NET Tutorial Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its kind of like a video journal that keeps track of my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/uLdNytpAIcI&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to upload all the code to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Zanark/L-NET/&quot;&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try my best to upload 1 video every 2 days, I hope I’ll be able to actually do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="youtube" /><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Interview Experience</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/01/My-Interview-Experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Interview Experience" /><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/01/My-Interview-Experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/07/01/My-Interview-Experience.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Hope you all are fine and dandy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as you can see, this is the first genuine post on my blog and I would like to make it as useful as possible.
Therefore, I’m going to share my interview experience here, hoping it might help some people out and provide
them with an idea of how the interview process looks and feels like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-0---written-exam&quot;&gt;ROUND 0 - Written Exam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exam was held on 19th June and the reporting time was 1PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s just skip to the meat(paneer if you are a vegetarian), the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Exam was held on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mettl.com/&quot;&gt;mettl&lt;/a&gt;, and it had 4 sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alloted Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 1 : Analytical and Quantitative – 20 Questions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;20 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 2 : Hands on Programming – 2 Questions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;25 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 3 : Tech MCQ – 20 Questions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;20 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Section 4 : Written English Test : 1 Question&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;20 Minutes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-1--analytical-and-quantitative&quot;&gt;Section 1 : Analytical and Quantitative&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relative Directional Questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete a pattern&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some Basic Maths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-2--hands-on-programming&quot;&gt;Section 2 : Hands on Programming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 basic programming puzzle questions where you’ll have to use different data structures and algorithms to get the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearing the hidden test cases is the key to clearing this round&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-3--tech-mcq&quot;&gt;Section 3 : Tech MCQ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DBMS, OS, and other theory based questions.
It had some networking questions as well. Many people struggled here, but people who have studied subjects out of the syllabus of the current semester were able to crack it(basically people who go to GATE or any other coaching classes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-4--written-english-test&quot;&gt;Section 4 : Written English Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we were given a topic to write an essay on.
The topic I got was - &lt;em&gt;The effect of media on one’s social development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of the written exam were declared on 22nd June, and luckily I was able to clear the written exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then asked to get ready for the Technical Interview which was going to be held on 24th June, yep, we had only 2 days to prepare for the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2 days of preparation, THE DAY came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my defence, I was &lt;strong&gt;REALLY&lt;/strong&gt; nervous. So if you saw me chowing down on chocolates and acting all goofy, I was basically trying to calm myself down with dopamine hits.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-1---the-technical-interview&quot;&gt;ROUND 1 - The Technical Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This round consisted of a one-on-one interview with one of the panel members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panel member asked for my Resume and briefly went through it.
&lt;br /&gt;
He then asked me one of the most feared questions: &lt;em&gt;” Tell me more about yourself “&lt;/em&gt;. Honestly, at first I was dumbfounded because I honestly wasn’t expecting that question in a technical round. I told him about my background and about all of my projects and the experience I gained in my internships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then started talking about my GitHub profile and about the open source projects that I’ve contributed to. He then checked my GitHub profile and my pinned repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the introductions, he gave me some simple math problems to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A friendly tip: BREATHE IN, BREATHE OUT, its okay to feel nervous, 
so take your time and calm down and solve the problem.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find such math problems on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/company-interview-corner/&quot;&gt;GeeksforGeeks&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuler.net/archives&quot;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt; and practice there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit that I was pretty nervous and it took me longer than expected to solve the questions, and the interviewer was also very friendly and provided me with some hints for which I respect him a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After discussing a bit more about my projects he asked me questions from Computer Science Fundamentals, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OOPs Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DBMS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Algorithms and Data Structures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Complexity and Space Complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also asked me to code some Dynamic Programming Algorithms. I wasn’t able to answer all the questions, but was able to give an outline of the approach one will take to solve the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it, I thanked the interviewer and headed back to the waiting room to join my peers banging their heads on the wall.&lt;br /&gt;
I too was really disappointed in myself for not being able to solve some of the basic questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-2---the-personal-interview&quot;&gt;ROUND 2 - The Personal Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard that I got selected for Round 2, I honestly couldn’t believe it. I tried my best to hold my racing heart and the excitement in and took deep breaths to calm myself down and then headed for the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered the interviewer’s cabin, greeted her and took a seat.&lt;br /&gt;
She asked me for my Resume and told me that she was pretty impressed by my GitHub profile.&lt;br /&gt;
I honestly cannot express how glad I was for mentioning my GitHub profile on my Resume and during the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;So remember kids, your GitHub profile is your second Resume.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then started talking about my experiences while developing the projects(both good and bad), internship experiences(both good and bad), my hobbies and interests, my weaknesses and how I keep myself updated in this ever-changing world of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also asked me some Client-Consultant scenario questions, about how I’ll solve a problem reported by a client and how I’ll keep the client updated on the progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was it, I thanked her and left the cabin with a huge smile because for me, the personal interview went really well and I was able to answer the interviewer’s questions well. I’ll be honest, I was proud of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;round-3---an-interview-with-the-hr&quot;&gt;ROUND 3 - An Interview with the HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a smile on my face and a boost in confidence from Round 2, I headed for the interview room for the 3rd round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HR was an incredibly friendly and charming person, a perfect gentleman. He actually asked me for my Resume on the doorstep and I almost dropped it while handing it to him, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then started going through my Resume and asked me about my Projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did I choose to make this project?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will I sell my project?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the world really need my solution to a problem whose solution already exists?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the person I am trying to convince to buy my product doesn’t agree at all then what should I do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was basically asked questions about my projects and what I can do with them and what kind of people is my project going to help and how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty confident and satisfied about how my third round went. I was even ready to accept rejection because this interview experience taught me a lot about how interviews go and what interviewers look for in a candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I calmed myself down and waited for my results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just kidding, I wasnt able to calm myself down. I couldn’t sit down in a place because when I did my stomach started feelling funny because of all that nervousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour of struggle to calm myself down, the panel members entered the room with the list of selected students, and yes, I got selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so happy that I just couldn’t stop smilling because of which my jaw muscles started to pain.
Now, I was just standing there with a locked jaw smiling like a goof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yep, that’s how my Interview went….in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will soon upload another post where I’ll add some Interview and Resume tips that I picked up from places on the internet. Until then goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, &lt;strong&gt;KEEP LEARNING NEW STUFF!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="interview" /><summary type="html">Hello everyone! Hope you all are fine and dandy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/22/First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2019-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/22/First-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/Blog//Blog/2019/06/22/First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently live streaming, hop in if you wanna see how much of an idiot i look like while programming lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube Channel Name: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwnUr0cB24YKbafp2wwQK2w&quot;&gt;ZANARK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwnUr0cB24YKbafp2wwQK2w/live&quot; title=&quot;My Live Stream&quot;&gt;Join me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="test" /><summary type="html">This is the first post on this blog.</summary></entry></feed>