<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-01T12:23:04+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Zanark’s Blog</title><subtitle>I’m a back-end web developer who loves to contribute to open source, tinker with ML/AI and develop games in my free time.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Book Review | THE 5AM CLUB</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2021/01/01/Book-Review-THE-5AM-CLUB.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review | THE 5AM CLUB" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2021/01/01/Book-Review-THE-5AM-CLUB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2021/01/01/Book-Review-THE-5AM-CLUB.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;quick-catchup&quot;&gt;Quick Catchup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! I wish everyone a Happy New Year! :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a really ong time since I last uploaded a post on this blog. Not gonna lie, I’ve been pretty lazy. However! It all changes starting today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My New Year Resolution:&lt;/em&gt;	Journal or Blog everyday (write something everyday to be exact)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help me keep myself accountable and improve my English and story writing skills for game development, oh and yeah, my typing speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to a year of productivity. Guess my theme is &lt;em&gt;Creativity&lt;/em&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now back to the Book Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;book-review&quot;&gt;Book Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;judging-the-book-by-its-cover&quot;&gt;Judging the book by its cover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well the cover looks great, the combination of mandarin orange and white looks really good. Gives me the vibes of a sunrise :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-1-to-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 1 to 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapters 1 to 8 are more like a prologue to the whole book. If you want to dive directly into the meat of the book then you’ll have to start from Chapter 9 where the author actually starts talking about the steps you can take every morning to Own your Morning, Elevate your Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dope-lines&quot;&gt;Dope Lines&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="BookReview" /><summary type="html">Quick Catchup</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Daily Morning Workout Routine</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/10/01/My-Daily-Morning-Workout-Routine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Daily Morning Workout Routine" /><published>2020-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/10/01/My-Daily-Morning-Workout-Routine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/10/01/My-Daily-Morning-Workout-Routine.html"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GMTK Game Jam 2020</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/08/22/GMTK-Game-Jam-2020-DevBlog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GMTK Game Jam 2020" /><published>2020-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/08/22/GMTK-Game-Jam-2020-DevBlog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/08/22/GMTK-Game-Jam-2020-DevBlog.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;gmtk-gamejam-devlog&quot;&gt;GMTK GameJam DevLog&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 30 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animation of you getting a notification from YouTube app that 
Mark just released a video
You click on the video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01:00 - 01:08
GMTK Game Jam Trailer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01:08 - 01:15
confetti&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01:15 - 3:00
Explain what GMTK channel is, ask ‘em to check it out, 
and tell em about the history of gmtk jam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:00 - 5:00
You are waiting for the video to premier on youtube which reveals the theme.
You are really excited and bang your head like a Tarsier Monkey.
Then Mark tells the theme and then the rest of the video’s background fads to audio
while you look at the screen with a face that says
“What the Fuck?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:00
Though ya I’ll admit the theme was pretty unique and when I heard the theme for the first time,
the only thing that came to my mid was ‘an infection out of control’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube: looks at you(shows the two finger “I have my eyes on you” thing)
me: I didnt even say the word&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways…
So you see an infection in the computer world will be called a malware
and whats the most anoying type of malware?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(random popups start coming on the screen….the screen gets floded with them)
yep…adware&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sat down and started noting down whatever came to mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Read out the blueprint]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realised, antiviruses nowadays are good enough to easily disable an adware.
So I switched to the 90s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;zoom out
Me: [Shouting] I said so I switched to the 90s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you glitch and now you have a 90s computer geek outfit on you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, there were two reasosn why i switched to  Win98 style graphics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll get an excuse for the adware being out of control cuz weak antivirus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The old operating systems had this pixelated UI and I always prefer pixel art when
creating a game for a jam cuz game jams are usually very short and pixel art does not take
too long to make.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So once I was done brainstorming, it was time to make some rough sketches&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drew a basic draft of how I wanted every game screen to look and how the gameplay
would progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Show the Visual Blueprint and explain]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Slideshow of the art made on day 1)
I then created the art for the game, as you can see its some basic pixel art with a Win16 palette that
comes preloaded in aseprite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I was done with the art, I started designing a few prototypes that I could send to some of my friends for some feedback and called it a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New day and with some fresh coffee(instant tho) and a fresh mind I was ready to get back to working
on my game.
Turns out my friends kinda liked the UI, and one of ‘em asked me to use a UI toolkit cuz that’d be better
however I wanted to go the self made assets way for this so I just made everything on aseprite, which took a while but I’m glad I chose to make it from scratch cuz this helped me learn how I can make buttons look like buttons in aseprite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the OS UI done, it was time to work on the coding part of the game, and boi am I a noob in GDScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t know, I use the Godot Engine for game development and GDScript is the native language used by godot which is kinda similar to Python, it works well on Linux so I find it more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay back to coding, I first started working on the buttons and other triggers for the game so that the transitions to different scenes will get smoother and after that I tried to work on the random adware pop up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well window popups in Godot come under the Control node and i’m not good at working with control nodes yet. So this took a long time and ate up the remaining time of day 2. But in the end I was able to get it work the way I wanted it to so I’m happy? I’ll dive into control nodes again when I get the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with the adware pop ups done, I then set up the title and end screen for the game and a tutorial for the players cuz my gameplay wasnt as structured and as smooth as I wanted it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WIth everything done, I set up an itch.io page fo rthe game and submitted it for the game jam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Record video of start screen, end screen and the itch io page]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(fade out to turbo reviewing your game)
Game review by Turbo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;end-card&quot;&gt;End Card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanx a ton Johnny Turbo for reviewing my game, check his channel out, he has some really good videos about game dev and how game dev works in the corporate world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanx a ton to everyone who checked out my game and rated it for the jam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ll see ya’all again, goodbye and keep learning new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="DevBlog" /><category term="YT-video-script" /><summary type="html">GMTK GameJam DevLog</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GameDev Diary #1</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/02/18/GameDev-Diary-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GameDev Diary #1" /><published>2020-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/02/18/GameDev-Diary-#1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/02/18/GameDev-Diary-1.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;gamedev-diary-1&quot;&gt;GameDev Diary #1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to learn C#, and whats the best way to learn C# other than making Games and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with MonoGame just like how a friend suggested, however I just cant bring up the motivation
to sit and work on it right now. Honestly, I have no idea where did all of my creative will vanish off to.
However, now I have some idea as to where I can start from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamefromscratch.com/post/2013/08/01/Just-starting-out-what-games-should-I-make.aspx&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; written by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCr-5TdGkKszdbboXXsFZJTQ&quot;&gt;Youtuber GamesFromScratch (check him out, he’s awesome)&lt;/a&gt; and realised something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot make a RPG games as a beginner, even though I have some programming language experience, I CANNOT!
NO ONE CAN! IT WIL TAKE TIME!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just don’t know why I was unable to understand something so obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I really dont wanna waste anymore time. Imma start today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html">GameDev Diary #1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Federated Learning</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/01/09/Federated-Learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Federated Learning" /><published>2020-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/01/09/Federated-Learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2020/01/09/Federated-Learning.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey all! Happy New Year! 2020!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been working on my machine learning skills which are pretty much non existent, and now I have been assigned a new task by my mentor…which is to learn  how federated learning works. So I’m just gonna document what I learned here. Hope its informative ^_^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;federated-learning&quot;&gt;Federated Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-federated-learning&quot;&gt;What is federated learning?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In federated learning the data is decentralised. This means that the data provided to the model is recieved from different sources simultaneously. For example getting data for a model form different mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-federated-learning&quot;&gt;Why federated learning?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventionally, the machine learning model works on the server and data is provided to the server by different clients. However this has some limitations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The server is online therefore poor internet will cause latency in getting results from the server, and such a case is not ideal for a model aiming for real-time results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The application cannot work offline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The network over which the data is sent is not secure enough therefore sensitive data can get leaked.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending and recieving data over a network is expensive for the battery and for the user as it’ll take up a lot of data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, what if the model is on the phone? This way teh model and the data is inside the moile phone.Well that has its own limitations as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s not enough data for the model.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Training and testing can use up a lot of battery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eg: What if a new word gets introduced in the dictionary and everyone else is using it but the user, this way the user doesn’t have the data for that word locally and the model will never know about it, and therefore this feature will never get discovered by the user unless he gets to know about it from an external source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well then, what if the model is pretrained a bit on the server using some proxy data, and then is sent to the clients for further training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solution might sound optimal but we can never decide on the perfect proxy data that can be used to pretrain the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in essence federated learning is kind of like collaborative learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the server send an initial model(which is not pretrained on any data) to all the clients. The clients then train and test the model on their own local data. When all the clients are done with trainig their models, their modified models is then pushed to the server which then takes an average of the modified model and send it back to the clients. So as you can see, we have a cycle here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-about-privacy&quot;&gt;Now about Privacy..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons why federated learning is so successfull is that it handles privacy really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The data never left the clients device =&amp;gt; sensitive data was never shared over the network =&amp;gt; secure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can trust the servers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Server cannot log any data from the clients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differential Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;: Each client adds some noise to the data they provide to the server. With a large number of clients, the noise generated on the       server-side creates a mask over the data it recieves which makes it difficult to point out individuality of the data still maintaing the progressibilty        of the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="machine-learning" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">Hey all! Happy New Year! 2020!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Linux Ricing</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/12/28/What-is-Linux-Ricing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Linux Ricing" /><published>2019-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/12/28/What-is-Linux-Ricing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/12/28/What-is-Linux-Ricing.html">&lt;p&gt;Yo ppl, guess the year is about to end and I havent uploaded a vid on my channel for a long time….nor have I posted nything on my blog here……kek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been asked by a lot of people - What the fuck is ricing? How do I do it?..and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So according to the favourite social hub of introverted virgin nerds(like me)…reddit and a subreddit where Arch users will never stop flexing, r/unixporn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Rice” is a word that is commonly used to refer to making visual improvements and customizations on one’s desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “ricing” was inheritted from the practice of customizing or modifying cars in Asia to make them look…..cool?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zanark/Blog/master/media/riced_car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;riced_car&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being racist, the word is accepted by the majority of the community and is used sparingly to refer to a visually attractive desktop upgraded beyond the default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so how does one start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-choose-your-distro&quot;&gt;1. Choose your distro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the unique and derived flavours of ice-creams, Linux has different distributions which have unique features and community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose which distro you want to work with and stick to it for atleast 2-3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most popular linux distros are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XUbuntu(xfce)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KUbuntu(KDE Plasma)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elementory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manjaro
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-choose-your-desktop-environment&quot;&gt;2. Choose your desktop environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desktop environment or DE is the part of the Operating System which handles the graphical user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have worked in the field of Web Development, a DE is basically the front end libraries you use to create a GUI for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of DE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KDE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xfce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gnome
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-choose-a-window-manager&quot;&gt;3. Choose a window manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A widow managers job is to manage windows…well no shit sherlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In simple words a window manager handles how the user can interact with the windows and how teh windows get displayed on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular window managers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xfce-wm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i3wm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bspwm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;awesomewm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-choose-your-terminal-emulator&quot;&gt;4. Choose your terminal emulator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terminal emulators handle how the terminal looks and allows you to customize the look if you dont like the default one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular terminal emulators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;xfce4-terminal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;urxvt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tmux
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-status-bars&quot;&gt;5. Status Bars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status bars are like the task bar on Windows. It’s just like an applet that you can customize to your hearts content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular status bars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;polybar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i3bar
…etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-theming-icons-and-fonts&quot;&gt;6. Theming, Icons and Fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding the best theme that suits your wallpaper can be quite tough. You can use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lxapperance&lt;/code&gt; to choose themes for your windows and mouse pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing fonts is the most iritating job during ricing, however once you get it done once, the same process can be copied to other distros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can hop over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xfce-look.org/&quot;&gt;xfcelook.org&lt;/a&gt; to download some awesome themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s it, its that easy. I’ll explain every step in its own post and will post soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, happy holidays and keep learning new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="youtube" /><summary type="html">Yo ppl, guess the year is about to end and I havent uploaded a vid on my channel for a long time….nor have I posted nything on my blog here……kek.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A brief explanation of the Dark Side of the Internet</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/11/18/Darknet-TW-Speech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A brief explanation of the Dark Side of the Internet" /><published>2019-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/11/18/Darknet-TW-Speech</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/11/18/Darknet-TW-Speech.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is kind of a support material for my TW speech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure by now everyone has heard about the Dark Web, commonly known as the epicenter of illegal and illicit online activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets start from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-origin-of-the-internet&quot;&gt;The Origin of the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1969 a couple of university students sent the world’s first computer-to-computer message. It was sent over ARPANET, an early ancestor of the internet. The concept of a network or a possible means of communication between two computers was the radical idea that set into motion the early stages of what we now call the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the internet continued to grow in the mid-to-late 1990s it would come to transform society on a global scale. The biggest change came in the form of instant communication. As long as you had an internet connection you could talk to anyone on earth, assuming, of course, they were also connected to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, the internet was not designed with things like anonymity and privacy in mind so everything you do and say online can and, in many cases, will be tracked, recorded, and traceable back to you. Some people are very concerned about their privacy and in the mid 1990s one such group of people was the United States federal government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-invention-of-tor&quot;&gt;The Invention of TOR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of computer scientists and mathematicians working for a branch of the US Navy known as the Naval Research Laboratory, abbreviated as NRL, began development of a new technology known as onion routing. Onion routing would allow for anonymous bi-directional communication where the source and destination cannot be determined by a mid-point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is accomplish by creating something known as an overlay network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overlay network is simply a network that is built on top of another network, in this case the internet. So instead of using the normal unencrypted internet, also known as the surface web, your traffic goes trough an overlay network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the people over at NRL soon realized a major limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The United States government can’t simply run an anonymity system for everybody and then use it themselves only because then
every time a connection came from it people would say “Oh, it’s another CIA agent looking at my website!” if those are the only
people using the network. So you need to have other people using the network so that they blend together.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;b&gt;ROGER DINGLEDINE&lt;/b&gt; (Co-Founder and Director of THE TOR PROJECT, speaking at a conference in 2004 )&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what he’s saying is that for the network to be truly anonymous it has to be available to everyone and not just the US government. So the NRL was forced to release their onion routing technology to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology was eventually released under an open source license and became TOR. TOR stands for The Onion Router and is the software you need to download to be able to access this network of onion routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, millions of people across the globe use TOR for a multitude of purposes. Everything from innocent daily browsing to criminal activities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And while it is the most popular, TOR is but one among numerous darknets. Together they all make up the dark web. Subsequently, the dark web forms a small part of the deep web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deep web is everything on the web that can not be indexed by search engines. It’s nothing like the dark web as most of us use the deep web all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-difference-between-dark-web-and-deep-web&quot;&gt;The difference between DARK WEB and DEEP WEB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fshawglobalnews.files.wordpress.com%2F2017%2F05%2Fdark-web-iceberg.jpg%3Fquality%3D70%26strip%3Dall%26strip%3Dall&amp;amp;f=1&amp;amp;nofb=1&quot; alt=&quot;A pictorail representation fo the internet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The deep web is content that can not be indexed by search engines. And the dark web is a fraction of the deep web consisting of numerous darknets which require specific software and/or authorization to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you make your Facebook profile private, search engines will not be able to find your profile. Even Facebook’s account search engine wont show your account as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, the deep web has a lot more content than the surface web. How much more? Well, we don’t know because by its very nature it’s near-impossible to determine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paper from 2001 estimated that the deep web is 500 times the size of the surface web but, then again, that estimation is almost over 2 decades old.
According to a more recent study, only 4% of the internet can be indexed by any search engines.&lt;br /&gt;
All we can say for certain is that deep web content accounts for the vast majority of the content on the world wide web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Web is just that small portion of deepweb which has extra security and is intentionally hidden from search engines.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;case-study---silk-road&quot;&gt;Case Study - Silk Road&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anonymity attracts a vast variety of people and can be used for both licit and illicit purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since the birth of the internet, people have used it for illegeal online activity. Infact one of the first E-Commerce transcations was a drug deal which was done in between two students at MIT Stanford in 1970.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October of 2013, the FBI took down the online drug marketplace known as Silk Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website had been in operation since the beginning of 2011 with a total revenue estimated at $1.2 billion. News about the Silk Road website brought the dark web out of the dark and right into public eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a few months after Silk Road had been taken down ex-administrators of the site launched Silk Road 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in late 2014, the FBI arrested the admins and the second marketplace was taken down as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few hours after that, Silk Road 3.0 was launched and the seemingly endless spiral continues. And keep in mind that Silk Road
was just one website among many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find numerous others just like it, selling every illegal drug you can imagine and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FBI also claimed that the owner of the Silk Road website had attempted to have six people killed by using deep web murder-for-hire services. While the assassinations themselves are unlikely to have occurred, these websites can definitely
be found on the dark web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.
.
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well yep I haven’t explained some stuff, especially how TOR works, I’m gonna explain that in another post that I’m working on right now and will upload soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="darknet" /><summary type="html">This is kind of a support material for my TW speech</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nope, not dead yet.</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/11/04/Nope-not-dead-yet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nope, not dead yet." /><published>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/11/04/Nope-not-dead-yet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/11/04/Nope-not-dead-yet.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Guys!! A new post on my dead blog lol :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it’s been a while since I last uploaded anything on my YouTube channel or on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well the thing is I hit a roadblock recently. I had no idea what to do and started to feel guilty about the time I have .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore I took a break this October, and I guess I have my motivation back. Expect some content soon!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">Hey Guys!! A new post on my dead blog lol :P</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Programmer stuck in a rut</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Programmer stuck in a rut" /><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/07/12/A-Programmer-in-a-rut.html">&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter how successful you are or how hard-working you are or how easily you can get motivated to do something, eventually you’ll reach a point in your life where you’ll start loosing interest in everything. You’ll start feeling comfortable with not challenging yourself anymore. You won’t be able to get inspired and motivated from any new challenges. You won’t be able to bring up the desire to take an action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that rendered you useless can be anything, it can be a bug which you’re just unable to rectify, it can be a badly documented API, or maybe its just because you are a JAVA Programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can actually come also after success as well, maybe you’re starting to feel less motivated while solving even the most challenging questions, maybe you are feeling comfortable with the status of your app and dont want to add any new features to ruin its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you can relate to anything close to what I mentioned above then you might be in a rut and its totally okay. Trust me it happens to the best of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to give you some of the best tips that I’ve learned from other people to get yourself out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-start-small&quot;&gt;1. Start Small.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in a rut, you just dont feel like doing anything, like nothing at all. Even the thought of a small task like setting up your bed can exhaust you and make you feel unmotivated instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of looking at the as a whole, break ‘em down to smaller tasks that you can complete quickly. This gives you a small shot of motivation and that sweet lil dope-a-mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting small is the key, you can then slowly combine everything and finish that task which was daunting on you without getting exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-set-your-priorities-and-use-your-time-judiciously&quot;&gt;2. Set your priorities and use your time judiciously.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create a time-table for the day, you must have found yourself putting every task at hand on the plate which make you run out of time to do other tasks. Trust me this happens to everyone. You might want to complete all the tasks in a single day but all of us only get 24 hrs, and &lt;strong&gt;sleep is important&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So set your priorities straight. If you want to have fun that day, then focus on what brings you joy at what time of the day and do not let anything disrupt the time alloted to fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stick to your priorities and you’ll be able to finish all the tasks and this time there wont be a pile of laundry on the back of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-dont-let-yourself-get-bored&quot;&gt;3. Don’t let yourself get bored.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boredom brings sadness. It’ll make you think about your life, all the bad choices you made in the past, whether you are happy or not etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It basically brings too much unpleasantness with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t let yourself get bored, go draw, learn something new, go out and play, try someone else’s Spotify playlist, watch a new movie/anime/tv-series/whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-connect-to-people-who-inspire-you&quot;&gt;4. Connect to people who inspire you.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the average of the 5 people you spend most of your time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you hang out with people who have achieved something in their lives or are striving towards achieving something, you get inspired do something in your life too. They might not know about this but they are your indirect mentors. Seeing them pursue something ignites a fire inside you and when this fire spreads to other people, they too get motivated to do something and then this cycle goes on and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these were a few tips that I’ve been trying to implement in my life since past 3 weeks and it has motivated me to keep on pushing harder and increase my work stamina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video that inspired me to write this Blog Post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zUr9n0Hy3PA&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So goodbye ppl, and keep learning new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="tips" /><category term="motivation" /><summary type="html">It doesn’t matter how successful you are or how hard-working you are or how easily you can get motivated to do something, eventually you’ll reach a point in your life where you’ll start loosing interest in everything. You’ll start feeling comfortable with not challenging yourself anymore. You won’t be able to get inspired and motivated from any new challenges. You won’t be able to bring up the desire to take an action.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My C# and .NET journal</title><link href="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/07/10/My-C-and-.NET-Journal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My C# and .NET journal" /><published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/07/10/My-C#-and-.NET-Journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zanark.github.io/blog//blog/2019/07/10/My-C-and-.NET-Journal.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zanark/Blog/master/media/CNET%20Thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;C# .NET Tutorial series Thumbail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve started a new series on my YouTube channel - C# and .NET Tutorial Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its kind of like a video journal that keeps track of my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/uLdNytpAIcI&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to upload all the code to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Zanark/L-NET/&quot;&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try my best to upload 1 video every 2 days, I hope I’ll be able to actually do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zanark</name></author><category term="youtube" /><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>